Hi, I'm Steve Anthony.
I'm a musician, singer, actor, based out of New York and Miami.
In this clip, we're going to talk about how to string a guitar.
Now I, as you can possibly see, I have replaced this string with a nice new string.
The rest of em', as you can see, are a little bit discolored and darkened with age.
They're getting old.
It's time to take em' off and put on some new ones.
First thing we do, we take our lovely multi-tool, which has a peg winder and a clipper.
Those are the two things we're going to need right away.
We're going to detune the string.
We're going to take tension off of the string until we hear no tone when we pluck it.
That's pretty much it.
And once we've released the tension from the string, we simply take our clipper and cut the string anywhere at all.
It doesn't really matter where.
In this case we're just right over the F hole.
And unwind the string from the tuning peg, toss it aside, and then using our multi-tool; as you can see, there's a little notch right here, would pop the bridge pin out and remove the string.
Now, you want to do this with all of the strings on the guitar.
Open up our package of strings, and what we're going to do is we're going to need our second string here, which actually is our fifth string, I'm sorry.
It's the A string. Take it out of the package, place the ball end back into the bridge slot, pop the bridge pin back in on top, press it in firmly, run the string through the nut, and give it a couple of turns around the the peg, and run the end of it through the hole in the peg.
And if that's not accessible, you can always turn the key a little bit so that it comes into a more advantageous position for you.
Run it through, snug it up a little bit, and then grab your peg winder, if you have it handy.
If you don't, you can just do it by hand.
Start cranking till' you get some tension on it, and that'll take up the slack in the peg.
And once you get the tension on the string you can take your clipper; cut the excess off, and then just repeat that procedure all the way down the guitar till' you've done it six times, and then you've restrung your guitar.
My name is Steve Anthony, and this has been how to string a guitar.